[
  {
    "question": "______ is the national symbol of India that is known for its colorful feathers",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Colorful", "Blue", "Dance", "Tail", "Feathers"],
    "answer": "Peacock",
    "source": "https://knowindia.india.gov.in/national-identity-elements/national-bird.php"

  },
  {
    "question": "_____ is a famous coffee drink that is traditionally prepared with steamed milk and is invented in Italy.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Expresso", "Foam", "Latte", "Frothy", "Cap"],
    "answer": "Cappuccino",
    "source": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cappuccino"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ is the second longest river in the world which represents 20% of the global riverine discharge into oceans.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Delivery", "Jeff", "Bezos", "Rainforest", "AWS"],
    "answer": "Amazon",
    "source": "https://www.indiatoday.in/education-today/gk-current-affairs/story/5-longest-rivers-world-1214680-2018-04-18"

  },
  {
    "question": "This famous painting by Leonardo da Vinci is known for its mysterious smile and is displayed in the Louvre Museum in Paris.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Gherardini", "Eyes", "Painting", "Artist", "Smile"],
    "answer": "Monalisa",
    "source": "https://www.louvre.fr/en/explore/the-palace/from-the-mona-lisa-to-the-wedding-feast-at-cana"
  },
  {
    "question": "This fruit is known for its appealing yellow peel and is a popular choice for a nutritious, on-the-go snack.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Monkey", "Yellow", "Peel", "Tree", "Tropical"],
    "answer": "Banana",
    "source": "https://www.britannica.com/plant/banana-plant"
  },
  {
    "question": "______ is a classic board game in which players buy and trade properties and attempt to bankrupt their opponents.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["money", "trading", "hotels", "houses", "mono"],
    "answer": "Monopoly",
    "source": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monopoly_(game)"
  },
  {
    "question": "______ are an ancient construction in Egypt, known for their massive size and precise alignment.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Giza", "Triangle", "Tomb", "sand", "Pharaoh"],
    "answer": "Pyramids",
    "source": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Pyramid_of_Giza"
  },
  {
    "question": "______ is a world-famous soft drink that was originally intended as a patent medicine and was invented in the late 19th century.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Coca", "Cola", "Soda", "Refreshment", "Red"],
    "answer": "Coke",
    "source": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coca-Cola"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________ is the second highest peak in the world that is 8,611 metres (28,251 ft) above sea level.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Everest", "Himalayas", "K2", "Pakistan", "two"],
    "answer": "K2",
    "source": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K2"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ is a legendary creature often depicted as a large, fire-breathing reptile with wings, known for its appearance in many mythologies and fantasy stories.",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Legendary", "Creature", "Fire-breathing", "Reptile", "Wings"],
    "answer": "Dragon",
    "source": "https://powerlisting.fandom.com/wiki/Dragon_Physiology"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the famous playwright known for writing tragedies like Macbeth?",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Shake", "Speare", "Hamlet", "Romeo", "Juliet"],
    "answer": "Shakespeare",
    "source": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the red planet in our solar system known for its thin atmosphere and potential for future human exploration?",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Red", "Chocolate", "Four", "rover", "NASA"],
    "answer": "Mars",
    "source": "https://science.nasa.gov/mars/"
  },
  {
    "question": "What AI-powered board game-playing program famously defeated the world champion Go player?",
    "forbiddenWords": ["AI-powered", "Board Game-playing", "Program", "Defeated", "World Champion", "Go Player"],
    "answer": "AlphaGo",
    "source": "https://deepmind.google/research/alphago/"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean and became an aviation pioneer?",
    "forbiddenWords": ["First Woman", "Fly Solo", "Atlantic Ocean", "Aviation Pioneer"],
    "answer": "Amelia",
    "source": "https://www.biography.com/"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which planet in our solar system has a ring system and is a gas giant composed predominantly of hydrogen and helium?",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Planet", "Solar System", "Ring System"],
    "answer": "Saturn",
    "source": "https://science.nasa.gov/solar-system/"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the famous scientist known for the theory of relativity?",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Famous Scientist", "Theory of Relativity"],
    "answer": "Einstein",
    "source": "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest mammal on Earth, renowned for its immense size and gentle nature?",
    "forbiddenWords": ["Blue", "Inhale", "Largest", "Size", "Shark"],
    "answer": "Whale",
    "source": "https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/mammals/facts/blue-whale"
  }

]
